Ellis Enobun

Front End Developer

Email: elnobun@gmail.com

Github: http://github.com/elnobun
LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/ellisenobun

Portfolio: https://ellisenobun.com/projects Mobile: 07954850837

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Detailed knowledge of Semantic HTML, CSS/SASS, Javascript and Modern Web Technologies for building accessible and performant web products, services and interfaces that are W.C.A.G 2.1 AAA compliant to meet users needs.
- Experience turning signed-off designs into usable and accessible user interfaces using plain HTML, CSS and Javascript (Vanilla).
- Experience in Automated Testing (Test-Driven Development and Cross-Platform Browser) to support continuous deployment environment and validate results, including progressive enhancement.
- Experience in Web Performance Optimisation (WPO) and resolving web security issues to ensure faster loading times without sacrificing functionality.
- Experience in Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) to organically increase website traffic through search results.
- Experience in using Version Control Systems like Git to track changes made to code over time.
- Experience using CMS (Control Management System) tools to enable prospective clients to manage data for products in a very efficient way.

COMMERCIAL PROJECTS:

<u>UHSports (University Of Hertfordshire Sports)</u>: A significant redesign of University of Hertfordshire Students Sports Website.

<u>Blackphone Privy2</u>: Developed Blackphone Privy2 NEW mobile security web service to improve the overall experience with a Blackphone Enterprise Privacy Platform.

<u>Lonsdale Services</u>: Developed Lonsdale Services with accessibility features to improve strategic financial long-term planning for pensioners aged 65+, retirees aged 50 and 60, and mortgagors aged 30 and 50.

https://puredrinks.co.uk/

See https://ellisenobun.com/projects for more.

WORK HISTORY

Lead FrontEnd Web Developer

Tonic Fusion LLP, UK. Web Design and Digital Marketing. Since May 2021

- Key responsibilities include: working with a team of designers and back-end developers to Build accessible and performant web interfaces across devices and browsers for many users regardless of their needs. Reporting of time management per project. Ensuring projects meet standards for Desktop and Mobile platforms. Undertaking browser testing to ensure the product meets high standards. Liaising with clients where necessary to undertake project briefs. Maintaining and backing up all work on hardware.
- Led the development of multiple enterprise-level web services like <u>UHSports (University Of Hertfordshire Sports)</u>, <u>Blackphone Privy2</u>, and <u>Lonsdale Financial Services</u>, resulting in a high percentage increase in user experience, page experience, and reduced bounce rates.
- Continuous technical analysis for web services like <u>Lonsdale Services UK</u>, <u>Brasstack Fittings UK</u>, <u>Fortune Financial UK</u>, and <u>Complete Tenders UK</u> resulted in a massive boost to SEO, Performance and User Accessibility, with a minimum of 85% increase in consumer conversion, retention and engagement.
- Implement fixes and integrate new features on <u>CivilService College</u>, <u>Amporshe Services & Engine Build Specialist UK</u>, <u>Barkleygreen UK</u>, <u>Deeset UK</u> web services, enabling in-depth improvement to user experience.
- Manage product development time to a specified budget while maintaining a high level of project delivery at all times.

Web Developer / Product Analyst

Digital Echos, UK.

Nov 2019 - May 2021

- Key responsibilities were to develop and maintain new websites for clients. Projects included building <u>Puredrinks Company E-Commerce Website</u> and <u>London Rangers Community Charity</u> website, with more than 70% on-time delivery while staying under budget.
- Played a vital role in the entire development lifecycle of projects, documenting system requirements, user requirements, use cases, user stories, wireframing design, coding and deployment.
- Handled technical issues on websites, ensuring websites were AAA compliant and Accessible, with standard SEO practices.
- Led a team of developers to redesign the <u>Company Website</u>, resulting in a reduction of 20% load times and a 15% increase in user accessibility.
- Led the transition from a waterfall web development method to a more efficient agile methodology, achieving an 80% increase in client satisfaction, data prediction and web development cycle.
- Executed tests daily, created defect reports and fixed bugs in web applications while ensuring proper documentation and information in all stages of a product life cycle.

Code Mentor / Reviewer

Udacity Inc. Mountain View & Sans Francisco, CA.

Jun 2016 - Nov 2019

- Reviewed code (new and existing) weekly to ensure quality assurance, web standards conformity, and responsibility for the code quality.
- Collaborated with a team of 6 to implement a Project Toolkit to help students fit into the digital programme by ascertaining strengths and weaknesses to boost student coding experience.
- Offered online support to students daily through a dedicated dashboard to improve industry standards' coding styles and skills.

EDUCATION

Masters Degree

The University of Leicester - Leicester City, United Kingdom Oct 2011 - Nov 2013

COURSES & TRAINING

FullStack Web Development:

Udacity Inc. Mountain View, United States. Jan 2015 - May 2016

LANGUAGES: English Language